<?xml version="1.0"?>
<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" class="examples">
<div class="example">
   <p>The paragraph below contains an abbreviation marked up with the
   <code><a href="#the-abbr-element">abbr</a></code> element. This paragraph <a href="#defining-term" title="defining&#10;   term">defines the term</a> "Web Hypertext Application Technology
   Working Group".</p>
   <pre><![CDATA[<p>The <dfn id=whatwg><abbr title="Web Hypertext Application
Technology Working Group">WHATWG</abbr></dfn> is a loose
unofficial collaboration of Web browser manufacturers and interested
parties who wish to develop new technologies designed to allow authors
to write and deploy Applications over the World Wide Web.</p>]]></pre>
   <p>An alternative way to write this would be:</p>
   <pre><![CDATA[<p>The <dfn id=whatwg>Web Hypertext Application Technology
Working Group</dfn> (<abbr title="Web Hypertext Application
Technology Working Group">WHATWG</abbr>) is a loose unofficial
collaboration of Web browser manufacturers and interested parties who
wish to develop new technologies designed to allow authors to write
and deploy Applications over the World Wide Web.</p>]]></pre>
  </div>
<div class="example">
   <p>This paragraph has two abbreviations. Notice how only one is
   defined; the other, with no expansion associated with it, does not
   use the <code><a href="#the-abbr-element">abbr</a></code> element.</p>
   <pre><![CDATA[<p>The <abbr title="Web Hypertext Application Technology Working
Group">WHATWG</abbr> started working on HTML5 in 2004.</p>]]></pre>
  </div>
<div class="example">
   <p>This paragraph links an abbreviation to its definition.</p>
   <pre><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="#whatwg"><abbr title="Web Hypertext Application
Technology Working Group">WHATWG</abbr></a> community does not
have much representation from Asia.</p>]]></pre>
  </div>
<div class="example">
   <p>This paragraph marks up an abbreviation without giving an
   expansion, possibly as a hook to apply styles for abbreviations
   (e.g. smallcaps).</p>
   <pre><![CDATA[<p>Philip` and Dashiva both denied that they were going to
get the issue counts from past revisions of the specification to
backfill the <abbr>WHATWG</abbr> issue graph.</p>]]></pre>
  </div>
<div class="example">

   <p>Here the plural is outside the element, so the expansion is in
   the singular:</p>

   <pre><![CDATA[<p>Two <abbr title="Working Group">WG</abbr>s worked on
this specification: the <abbr>WHATWG</abbr> and the
<abbr>HTMLWG</abbr>.</p>]]></pre>

   <p>Here the plural is inside the element, so the expansion is in
   the plural:</p>

   <pre><![CDATA[<p>Two <abbr title="Working Groups">WGs</abbr> worked on
this specification: the <abbr>WHATWG</abbr> and the
<abbr>HTMLWG</abbr>.</p>]]></pre>

  </div>

</div>
