<?xml version="1.0"?>
<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" class="examples">
<div class="example">

   <p>In this example, some completely-unknown, potentially hostile,
   user-provided HTML content is embedded in a page. Because it is
   sandboxed, it is treated by the user agent as being from a unique
   origin, despite the content being served from the same site. Thus
   it is affected by all the normal cross-site restrictions. In
   addition, the embedded page has scripting disabled, plugins
   disabled, forms disabled, and it cannot navigate any frames or
   windows other than itself (or any frames or windows it itself
   embeds).</p>

   <pre><![CDATA[<p>We're not scared of you! Here is your content, unedited:</p>
<iframe sandbox src="getusercontent.cgi?id=12193"></iframe>]]></pre>

   <p>Note that cookies are still send to the server in the <code title="">getusercontent.cgi</code> request, though they are not
   visible in the <code title="dom-document-cookies">document.cookies</code> DOM
   attribute.</p>

  </div>
<div class="example">

   <p>In this example, a gadget from another site is embedded. The
   gadget has scripting and forms enabled, and the origin sandbox
   restrictions are lifted, allowing the gadget to communicate with
   its originating server. The sandbox is still useful, however, as it
   disables plugins and popups, thus reducing the risk of the user
   being exposed to malware and other annoyances.</p>

   <pre><![CDATA[<iframe sandbox="allow-same-origin allow-forms allow-scripts"
        src="http://maps.example.com/embedded.html"></iframe>]]></pre>

  </div>
<div class="example">

   <p>In this example, the site's navigation is embedded using a
   client-side include using an <code><a href="#the-iframe-element">iframe</a></code>. Any links in the
   <code><a href="#the-iframe-element">iframe</a></code> will, in new user agents, be automatically
   opened in the <code><a href="#the-iframe-element">iframe</a></code>'s parent browsing context; for
   legacy user agents, the site could also include a <code><a href="#the-base-element">base</a></code>
   element with a <code title="attr-base-target"><a href="#attr-base-target">target</a></code>
   attribute with the value <code title="">_parent</code>. Similarly,
   in new user agents the styles of the parent page will be
   automatically applied to the contents of the frame, but to support
   legacy user agents authors might wish to include the styles
   explicitly.</p>

   <pre><![CDATA[<nav><iframe seamless src="nav.include.html"></iframe></nav>]]></pre>

  </div>

</div>
