<?xml version="1.0"?>
<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" class="examples">
<div class="example">

   <p>A single image can have different appropriate alternative text
   depending on the context.</p>

   <p>In each of the following cases, the same image is used, yet the
   <code title="attr-img-alt"><a href="#attr-img-alt">alt</a></code> text is different each
   time. The image is the coat of arms of the Canton Geneva in
   Switzerland.</p>

   <p>Here it is used as a supplementary icon:</p>
   <pre><![CDATA[<p>I lived in <img src="carouge.svg" alt=""> Carouge.</p>]]></pre>

   <p>Here it is used as an icon representing the town:</p>
   <pre><![CDATA[<p>Home town: <img src="carouge.svg" alt="Carouge"></p>]]></pre>

   <p>Here it is used as part of a text on the town:</p>

   <pre><![CDATA[<p>Carouge has a coat of arms.</p>
<p><img src="carouge.svg" alt="The coat of arms depicts a lion, sitting in front of a tree."></p>
<p>It is used as decoration all over the town.</p>]]></pre>

   <p>Here it is used as a way to support a similar text where the
   description is given as well as, instead of as an alternative to,
   the image:</p>

   <pre><![CDATA[<p>Carouge has a coat of arms.</p>
<p><img src="carouge.svg" alt=""></p>
<p>The coat of arms depicts a lion, sitting in front of a tree.
It is used as decoration all over the town.</p>]]></pre>

   <p>Here it is used as part of a story:</p>

   <pre><![CDATA[<p>He picked up the folder and a piece of paper fell out.</p>
<p><img src="carouge.svg" alt="Shaped like a shield, the paper had a
red background, a green tree, and a yellow lion with its tongue
hanging out and whose tail was shaped like an S."></p>
<p>He stared at the folder. S! The answer he had been looking for all
this time was simply the letter S! How had he not seen that before? It all
came together now. The phone call where Hector had referred to a lion's tail,
the time Marco had stuck his tongue out...</p>]]></pre>

   <p>Here it is not known at the time of publication what the image
   will be, only that it will be a coat of arms of some kind, and thus
   no replacement text can be provided, and instead only a brief
   caption for the image is provided, in the <code title="attr-title"><a href="#the-title-attribute">title</a></code> attribute:</p>

   <pre><![CDATA[<p>The last user to have uploaded a coat of arms uploaded this one:</p>
<p><img src="last-uploaded-coat-of-arms.cgi" title="User-uploaded coat of arms."></p>]]></pre>

   <p>Ideally, the author would find a way to provide real replacement
   text even in this case, e.g. by asking the previous user. Not
   providing replacement text makes the document more difficult to use
   for people who are unable to view images, e.g. blind users, or
   users or very low-bandwidth connections or who pay by the byte, or
   users who are forced to use a text-only Web browser.</p>

  </div>
<div class="example">

   <p>Here are some more examples showing the same picture used in
   different contexts, with different appropriate alternate texts each
   time.</p>

   <pre><![CDATA[<article>
 <h1>My cats</h1>
 <h2>Fluffy</h2>
 <p>Fluffy is my favourite.</p>
 <img src="fluffy.jpg" alt="She likes playing with a ball of yarn.">
 <p>She's just too cute.</p>
 <h2>Miles</h2>
 <p>My other cat, Miles just eats and sleeps.</p>
</article>]]></pre>

   <pre><![CDATA[<article>
 <h1>Photography</h1>
 <h2>Shooting moving targets indoors</h2>
 <p>The trick here is to know how to anticipate; to know at what speed and
 what distance the subject will pass by.</p>
 <img src="fluffy.jpg" alt="A cat flying by, chasing a ball of yarn, can be
 photographed quite nicely using this technique.">
 <h2>Nature by night</h2>
 <p>To achieve this, you'll need either an extremely sensitive film, or
 immense flash lights.</p>
</article>]]></pre>

   <pre><![CDATA[<article>
 <h1>About me</h1>
 <h2>My pets</h2>
 <p>I've got a cat named Fluffy and a dog named Miles.</p>
 <img src="fluffy.jpg" alt="Fluffy, my cat, tends to keep itself busy.">
 <p>My dog Miles and I like go on long walks together.</p>
 <h2>music</h2>
 <p>After our walks, having emptied my mind, I like listening to Bach.</p>
</article>]]></pre>

   <pre><![CDATA[<article>
 <h1>Fluffy and the Yarn</h1>
 <p>Fluffy was a cat who liked to play with yarn. He also liked to jump.</p>
 <aside><img src="fluffy.jpg" alt="" title="Fluffy"></aside>
 <p>He would play in the morning, he would play in the evening.</p>
</article>]]></pre>

  </div>
<div class="example">

   <p>In this example, a user is asked to pick his preferred color
   from a list of three. Each color is given by an image, but for
   users who have configured their user agent not to display images,
   the color names are used instead:</p>

   <pre><![CDATA[<h1>Pick your color</h1>
<ul>
 <li><a href="green.html"><strong><img src="green.jpeg" alt="Green"></strong></a></li>
 <li><a href="blue.html"><strong><img src="blue.jpeg" alt="Blue"></strong></a></li>
 <li><a href="red.html"><strong><img src="red.jpeg" alt="Red"></strong></a></li>
</ul>]]></pre>

  </div>
<div class="example">

   <p>In this example, each button has a set of images to indicate the
   kind of color output desired by the user. The first image is used
   in each case to give the alternative text.</p>

   <pre><![CDATA[<button name="rgb"><strong><img src="red" alt="RGB"><img src="green" alt=""><img src="blue" alt=""></strong></button>
<button name="cmyk"><strong><img src="cyan" alt="CMYK"><img src="magenta" alt=""><img src="yellow" alt=""><img src="black" alt=""></strong></button>]]></pre>

   <p>Since each image represents one part of the text, it could also
   be written like this:</p>

   <pre><![CDATA[<button name="rgb"><strong><img src="red" alt="R"><img src="green" alt="G"><img src="blue" alt="B"></strong></button>
<button name="cmyk"><strong><img src="cyan" alt="C"><img src="magenta" alt="M"><img src="yellow" alt="Y"><img src="black" alt="K"></strong></button>]]></pre>

   <p>However, with other alternative text, this might not work, and
   putting all the alternative text into one image in each case might
   make more sense:</p>

   <pre><![CDATA[<button name="rgb"><strong><img src="red" alt="sRGB profile"><img src="green" alt=""><img src="blue" alt=""></strong></button>
<button name="cmyk"><strong><img src="cyan" alt="CMYK profile"><img src="magenta" alt=""><img src="yellow" alt=""><img src="black" alt=""></strong></button>]]></pre>

  </div>
<div class="example">

   <p>In the following example we have <a href="images/parsing-model-overview.png">a flowchart</a> in image
   form, with text in the <code title="attr-img-alt"><a href="#attr-img-alt">alt</a></code>
   attribute rephrasing the flowchart in prose form:</p>

   <pre><![CDATA[<p>In the common case, the data handled by the tokenization stage
comes from the network, but it can also come from script.</p>
<p><strong><img src="images/parsing-model-overview.png" alt="The network
passes data to the Tokeniser stage, which passes data to the Tree
Construction stage. From there, data goes to both the DOM and to
Script Execution. Script Execution is linked to the DOM, and, using
document.write(), passes data to the Tokeniser."></strong></p>]]></pre>

  </div>
<div class="example">

   <p>Here's another example, showing a good solution and a bad
   solution to the problem of including an image in a
   description.</p>

   <p>First, here's the good solution. This sample shows how the
   alternative text should just be what you would have put in the
   prose if the image had never existed.</p>

   <pre><![CDATA[<!-- This is the correct way to do things. -->
<p>
 You are standing in an open field west of a house.
 <strong><img src="house.jpeg" alt="The house is white, with a boarded front door."></strong>
 There is a small mailbox here.
</p>]]></pre>

   <p>Second, here's the bad solution. In this incorrect way of
   doing things, the alternative text is simply a description of the
   image, instead of a textual replacement for the image. It's bad
   because when the image isn't shown, the text doesn't flow as well
   as in the first example.</p>

   <pre class="bad"><!-- <em>This is the wrong way to do things.</em> -->
<p>
 You are standing in an open field west of a house.
 <img src="house.jpeg" alt="A white house, with a boarded front door.">
 There is a small mailbox here.
</p>]]></pre>

  </div>
<div class="example">

   <p>Here the icons are next to text that conveys the same meaning,
   so they have an empty <code title="attr-img-alt"><a href="#attr-img-alt">alt</a></code>
   attribute:</p>

   <pre><![CDATA[<nav>
 <p><a href="/help/"><strong><img src="/icons/help.png" alt=""></strong> Help</a></p>
 <p><a href="/configure/"><strong><img src="/icons/configuration.png" alt=""></strong>
 Configuration Tools</a></p>
</nav>]]></pre>

  </div>
<div class="example">

   <p>Here, posts on a news site are labeled with an icon
   indicating their topic.</p>

   <pre><![CDATA[<body>
 <article>
  <header>
   <h1>Ratatouille wins <i>Best Movie of the Year</i> award</h1>
   <p><strong><img src="movies.png" alt="Movies"></strong></p>
  </header>
  <p>Pixar has won yet another <i>Best Movie of the Year</i> award,
  making this its 8th win in the last 12 years.</p>
 </article>
 <article>
  <header>
   <h1>Latest TWiT episode is online</h1>
   <p><strong><img src="podcasts.png" alt="Podcasts"></strong></p>
  </header>
  <p>The latest TWiT episode has been posted, in which we hear
  several tech news stories as well as learning much more about the
  iPhone. This week, the panelists compare how reflective their
  iPhones' Apple logos are.</p>
 </article>
</body>]]></pre>

  </div>
<div class="example">

   <p>In the following snippets, all four of the above cases are
   present. First, we see a logo used to represent a company:</p>

   <pre><![CDATA[<h1><strong><img src="XYZ.gif" alt="The XYZ company"></strong></h1>]]></pre>

   <p>Next, we see a paragraph which uses a logo right next to the
   company name, and so doesn't have any alternative text:

   </p><pre><![CDATA[<article>
 <h2>News</h2>
 <p>We have recently been looking at buying the <strong><img src="alpha.gif"
 alt=""> ΑΒΓ company</strong>, a small Greek company
 specializing in our type of product.</p>]]></pre>

   <p>In this third snippet, we have a logo being used in an aside,
   as part of the larger article discussing the acquisition:</p>

<pre><![CDATA[ <strong><aside><p><img src="alpha-large.gif" alt=""></p></aside></strong>
 <p>The ΑΒΓ company has had a good quarter, and our
 pie chart studies of their accounts suggest a much bigger blue slice
 than its green and orange slices, which is always a good sign.</p>
</article>]]></pre>

   <p>Finally, we have an opinion piece talking about a logo, and
   the logo is therefore described in detail in the alternative
   text.</p>

   <pre><![CDATA[<p>Consider for a moment their logo:</p>

<strong><p><img src="/images/logo" alt="It consists of a green circle with a
green question mark centered inside it."></p></strong>

<p>How unoriginal can you get? I mean, oooooh, a question mark, how
<em>revolutionary</em>, how utterly <em>ground-breaking</em>, I'm
sure everyone will rush to adopt those specifications now! They could
at least have tried for some sort of, I don't know, sequence of
rounded squares with varying shades of green and bold white outlines,
at least that would look good on the cover of a blue book.</p>]]></pre>

   <p>This example shows how the alternative text should be written
   such that if the image isn't <i>available</i>, and the text is used
   instead, the text flows seamlessly into the surrounding text, as
   if the image had never been there in the first place.</p>

  </div>
<div class="example">

   <p>Consider a graphic containing the text "Earth Day", but with the
   letters all decorated with flowers and plants. If the text is
   merely being used as a header, to spice up the page for graphical
   users, then the correct alternative text is just the same text
   "Earth Day", and no mention need be made of the decorations:</p>

   <pre><![CDATA[<h1><strong><img src="earthdayheader.png" alt="Earth Day"></strong></h1>]]></pre>

  </div>
<div class="example">

   <p>A flowchart that repeats the previous paragraph in graphical form:</p>

   <pre><![CDATA[<p>The network passes data to the Tokeniser stage, which
passes data to the Tree Construction stage. From there, data goes
to both the DOM and to Script Execution. Script Execution is
linked to the DOM, and, using document.write(), passes data to
the Tokeniser.</p>
<strong><p><img src="images/parsing-model-overview.png" alt=""></p></strong>]]></pre>

   <p>In these cases, it would be wrong to include alternative text
   that consists of just a caption. If a caption is to be included,
   then either the <code title="attr-title"><a href="#the-title-attribute">title</a></code> attribute can
   be used, or the <code><a href="#the-figure-element">figure</a></code> and <code><a href="#the-legend-element">legend</a></code>
   elements can be used. In the latter case, the image would in fact
   be a phrase or paragraph with an alternative graphical
   representation, and would thus require alternative text.</p>

   <pre><![CDATA[<!-- Using the title="" attribute -->
<p>The network passes data to the Tokeniser stage, which
passes data to the Tree Construction stage. From there, data goes
to both the DOM and to Script Execution. Script Execution is
linked to the DOM, and, using document.write(), passes data to
the Tokeniser.</p>
<p><strong><img src="images/parsing-model-overview.png" alt=""
        title="Flowchart representation of the parsing model."></strong></p>]]></pre>

   <pre><![CDATA[<!-- Using <figure> and <legend> -->
<p>The network passes data to the Tokeniser stage, which
passes data to the Tree Construction stage. From there, data goes
to both the DOM and to Script Execution. Script Execution is
linked to the DOM, and, using document.write(), passes data to
the Tokeniser.</p>
<figure>
 <strong><img src="images/parsing-model-overview.png" alt="The Network leads
 to the Tokeniser, which leads to the Tree Construction. The Tree
 Construction leads to two items. The first is Script Execution, which
 leads via document.write() back to the Tokeniser. The second item
 from which Tree Construction leads is the DOM. The DOM is related to
 the Script Execution."></strong>
 <legend>Flowchart representation of the parsing model.</legend>
</figure>]]></pre>

   <pre class="bad"><!-- This is WRONG. Do not do this. Instead, do what the above examples do. -->
<p>The network passes data to the Tokeniser stage, which
passes data to the Tree Construction stage. From there, data goes
to both the DOM and to Script Execution. Script Execution is
linked to the DOM, and, using document.write(), passes data to
the Tokeniser.</p>
<p><img src="images/parsing-model-overview.png"
        alt="Flowchart representation of the parsing model."></p>
<!-- Never put the image's caption in the alt="" attribute! -->]]></pre>

  </div>
<div class="example">

   <p>A graph that repeats the previous paragraph in graphical form:</p>

   <pre><![CDATA[<p>According to a study covering several billion pages,
about 62% of documents on the Web in 2007 triggered the Quirks
rendering mode of Web browsers, about 30% triggered the Almost
Standards mode, and about 9% triggered the Standards mode.</p>
<strong><p><img src="rendering-mode-pie-chart.png" alt=""></p></strong>]]></pre>

  </div>
<div class="example">

   <p>Examples where the image is purely decorative despite being
   relevant would include things like a photo of the Black Rock City
   landscape in a blog post about an event at Burning Man, or an
   image of a painting inspired by a poem, on a page reciting that
   poem. The following snippet shows an example of the latter
   case (only the first verse is included in this snippet):</p>

   <pre><![CDATA[<h1>The Lady of Shalott</h1>
<strong><p><img src="shalott.jpeg" alt=""></p></strong>
<p>On either side the river lie<br>
Long fields of barley and of rye,<br>
That clothe the wold and meet the sky;<br>
And through the field the road run by<br>
To many-tower'd Camelot;<br>
And up and down the people go,<br>
Gazing where the lilies blow<br>
Round an island there below,<br>
The island of Shalott.</p>]]></pre>

  </div>
<div class="example">

   <p>In the following example, a picture representing a company logo
   for <span title="">XYZ Corp</span> has been split into two pieces,
   the first containing the letters "XYZ" and the second with the word
   "Corp". The alternative text ("XYZ Corp") is all in the first
   image.</p>

   <pre><![CDATA[<h1><strong><img src="logo1.png" alt="XYZ Corp"><img src="logo2.png" alt=""></strong></h1>]]></pre>

  </div>
<div class="example">

   <p>In the following example, a rating is shown as three filled
   stars and two empty stars. While the alternative text could have
   been "★★★☆☆", the author has
   instead decided to more helpfully give the rating in the form
   "3/5". That is the alternative text of the first image, and the
   rest have blank alternative text.</p>

   <pre><![CDATA[<p>Rating: <meter max=5 value=3><strong><img src="1" alt="3/5"
  ><img src="1" alt=""><img src="1" alt=""><img src="0" alt=""
  ><img src="0" alt=""></strong></meter></p>]]></pre>

  </div>
<div class="example">

   <p>In the following example, a picture representing the flying
   spaghetti monster emblem, with each of the left noodly appendages
   and the right noodly appendages in different images, so that the
   user can pick the left side or the right side in an adventure.</p>

   <pre><![CDATA[<h1>The Church</h1>
<p>You come across a flying spaghetti monster. Which side of His
Noodliness do you wish to reach out for?</p>
<strong><p><a href="?go=left" ><img src="fsm-left.png"  alt="Left side. "></a
  ><img src="fsm-middle.png" alt=""
  ><a href="?go=right"><img src="fsm-right.png" alt="Right side."></a></p></strong>]]></pre>

  </div>

</div>
