<?xml version="1.0"?>
<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" class="examples">
<div class="example">

   <p>Banks frequently do not want UAs to prefill login
   information:</p>

   <pre><![CDATA[<p>Account: <input type="text" name="ac" autocomplete="off"></p>
<p>PIN: <input type="text" name="pin" autocomplete="off"></p>]]></pre>

  </div>
<div class="example">
   <p>For example, the following snippet:</p>
   <pre><![CDATA[
<label> Part number:
 <input pattern="[0-9][A-Z]{3}" name="part"
        title="A part number is a digit followed by three uppercase letters."/>
</label>
]]></pre>
   <p>...could cause the UA to display an alert such as:</p>
   <pre><![CDATA[<samp> part number is a digit followed by three uppercase letters.
You cannot complete this form until the field is correct.</samp>]]></pre>
  </div>
<p class="example">For instance, if the title attribute contained
  the caption of the control, assistive technology could end up saying
  something like <samp>The text you have entered does not match the
  required pattern. Birthday</samp>, which is not useful.</p>
<div class="example">

   <p>Here is an example of a mail configuration user interface that
   uses the <code title="attr-input-placeholder"><a href="#attr-input-placeholder">placeholder</a></code>
   attribute:</p>

   <pre><![CDATA[<fieldset>
 <legend>Mail Account</legend>
 <p><label>Name: <input type="text" name="fullname" placeholder="John Ratzenberger"></label></p>
 <p><label>Address: <input type="email" name="address" placeholder="john@example.net"></label></p>
 <p><label>Password: <input type="password" name="password"></label></p>
 <p><label>Description: <input type="text" name="desc" placeholder="My Email Account"></label></p>
</fieldset>]]></pre>

  </div>
<p class="example">Examples of a user changing the element's <a href="#concept-fe-value" title="concept-fe-value">value</a> would include the user typing
  into a text field, pasting a new value into the field, or undoing an
  edit in that field. Some user interactions do not cause changes to
  the value, e.g. hitting the "delete" key in an empty text field, or
  replacing some text in the field with text from the clipboard that
  happens to be exactly the same text.</p>
<p class="example">An example of a user interface with a commit
  action would be a <a href="#file-upload-state" title="attr-input-type-file">File
  Upload</a> control that consists of a single button that brings
  up a file selection dialog: when the dialog is closed, if that the
  <a href="#concept-input-type-file-selected" title="concept-input-type-file-selected">file selection</a>
  changed as a result, then the user has commited a new <a href="#concept-input-type-file-selected" title="concept-input-type-file-selected">file selection</a>.</p>
<p class="example">Another example of a user interface with a commit
  action would be a <a href="#date-state" title="attr-input-type-date">Date</a>
  control that allows both text-based user input and user selection
  from a drop-down calendar: while text input might not have an
  explicit commit step, selecting a date from the drop down calendar
  and then dismissing the drop down would be a commit action.</p>

</div>
